Guide to the DeLaney Kiphuth, Special Assistant to the President of Yale University for Athletics, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
DeLaney Kiphuth, special assistant to the president of Yale University for athletics, Records
1965-1981
RU 726
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.25
(4 boxes)
The records consist of applications, reports, correspondence, committee notes, budgets, films, studies, fellowships, questionnaires, and recommendations documenting Special Assistant DeLaney Kiphuth's interests concerning athletics at Yale University.
Yale University. President's Office
Kiphuth, Delaney
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-B (YRG 2-B), Records of Yale presidential assistants.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See inventory for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of applications, reports, correspondence, committee notes, budgets, films, studies, fellowships, questionnaires, and recommendations documenting Special Assistant DeLaney Kiphuth's interests concerning athletics at Yale University.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Athletics; College sports; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University. President's Office
- Records of special assistant DeLaney Kiphuth concerning athletics, 1965-1981; Accession 1983-A-087
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2017.
  - Admissions, Athletic-Related (Class of 1980) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Association of Universities (AAU), 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American College of Sports Medicine, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Applications
    - Fencing, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Trainer, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Association of Yale Alumni, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Y" Society, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Athletics, Physical Education and Recreation, Department of
    - Budget, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Consumers Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Council Committee on Athletics, Yale, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Athletic Director - Miscellaneous, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Facilities and Activities for Bulletin of the Graduate School, Athletic, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Executive Committee, Athletic, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Jones Report
      - Report of the Commission on Athletics, 1976 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Comments, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - And Related Items, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Legal Matters - Yale Athletics, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Liquor - Yale Athletics, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Materials Mailed to Incoming Students, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Procedures for Electing Captains, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Ray Tompkins House - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Athletics, Sports
    - Basketball, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Basketball - Women's, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Crew, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - International Rowing Course Foundation, Inc., 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - Lightweight Crew, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Fencing, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Football, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - Football Centennial Dinner-New Haven, 1972 November 17 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - Football "Y" Association, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Figure Skating Club
      - 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Golf Course Advisory Committee, Yale, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Hockey
      - 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 54)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Hockey Association
      - 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 56)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 57)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 58)
      - Pee Wee Hockey Program, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Intercollegiate Athletics at Yale, Report 1973 August 31 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Soccer, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Soccer/Lacrosse (Barry Svigals), 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Swim Club, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Swimming, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Swimming Film - (Tony Stewart/Katie Burnett), 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Swimming - Women, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Tennis, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Tennis, Platform (Bettendorf) (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Tennis (Tyng Cup), 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Track (Yale/Harvard - Oxford/Cambridge), 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Track, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Women's Athletics, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Women's Sports, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Wrestling, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Awards/Scholarships, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Scholarships - Rossbach, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Boys' Clubs of America, Inc., 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Copies of Acknowledgement of Contribution
      - 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 91)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 92)
      - 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Budget - Department of Athletics, Physical Education and Recreation, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 94 - 96)
  - Calendar, Yale College, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Candidates for Admission, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 99 - 102)
  - Commencement, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Committee on Coaches (Report of Committee), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Complaints, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Corporation Members (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Eastern College Athletic Conference, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Exercise Programs, 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Facilities
    - Cullman Courts, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Eggers and Higgins Report, 1969 March 18 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Inventory, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Lagoon, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Payne Whitney Gymnasium Addition, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Report of the Committee on Facilities, 1973 February 19 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Soccer/Lacrosse Field, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Use by Outside Group (Bicentennial and Bowl), 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Negotiations with NASL for use of Bowl, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Rules on use by outside groups, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Films, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Football "Y" News, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Gerald Ford, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Greenwich YMCA (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Gymnasium, Payne Whitney, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - Yale History, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Invitations, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Ivy (Tenth Football Game), 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 132)
    - Proposal for a Tenth Football Game, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Ivy Athletic Directors, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 134)
    - Eligibility, 1976-1980 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Ivy Colleges
    - Dartmouth, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 138)
    - Harvard, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 139)
    - Princeton, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Journal Article
    - Cohane Football History, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - Miscellaneous, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 155)
  - National Art Museum of Sport, Inc., 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 160)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association - (Certification of Compliance), 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 161)
    - Convention, 1977 January (Box 2, Folder 162)
    - 71st Convention Amendment Procedures, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 163)
    - Division Classification Commission, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 164)
    - General, 1976-1980 (Box 2, Folder 165)
    - NCAA and AIAW Organization (Newspaper clippings) (Box 2, Folder 166)
    - NCAA Marketing, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 167)
    - NCAA and Minn. Probation, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 168)
    - Postgraduate Scholarships, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 169)
    - Reorganization of Div. I - 77 Convention, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 171)
    - Suggestions for Presidential Nominees, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 172)
    - Volunteers for Youth, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 173)
  - Olympic Sports, President's Commission on, 1976 April 10 (Box 3, Folder 174)
  - Outdoor Recreation Center, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 175)
  - Personal - DeLaney Kiphuth
    - Class of 1941, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 176)
    - DKE (Delta Kappa Epsilon), 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 177)
    - 1940 Football Team, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - United Way, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 180)
  - Physical Education Budget, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 181)
  - Practice Pool - Bulkhead (Box 3, Folder 182)
  - President's Office, Organization of, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 183)
    - Hanna H. Gray (Provost and Acting President), 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 184)
  - Provost's Office (Box 3, Folder 189)
  - Questionnaires (Box 3, Folder 192)
  - Recommendations
    - 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 193)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 194)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 195)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 196)
  - Reunions (Box 4, Folder 197)
  - Seven Springs Center, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 201)
  - Special Scientific Projects (National Library of Medicine), 1977 May 11 (Box 4, Folder 202)
  - Special Scientific Projects, Ad Hoc Discussion Group, 1977 May 11 (Box 4, Folder 203)
  - Speeches (Box 4, Folder 204)
  - Stanford (Box 4, Folder 205)
  - Stanford University Youth Program (Box 4, Folder 206)
  - Sweet Briar College, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 207)
  - TIAA/CREF (1977 Annual Report) (Box 4, Folder 208)
  - Title IX, 1976-1977, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 209)
  - Yale University
    - Art Gallery, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 210)
    - Band, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 211)
    - Bowl, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 212)
    - Charities Drive, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 213)
    - Clubs, Yale, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 214)
    - Faculty Club, Yale, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 215)
    - Library, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 216)
    - Medal, Yale, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 217)
    - Miscellaneous - Yale Alumni Placement Service; Yale Graduate School Association; Yale College Internship Program (Box 4, Folder 218)